(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pot.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine and today we've got
an elementary level lesson for you
all about getting up in the morning.
- That's right, today
we're making breakfast
and well, of course many
people have different things
when they're making
breakfast and we're very big.
Others are small, but this is
what we're gonna talk about today.
So why don't we listen to the dialogue
and see what they're
having for breakfast today.
(upbeat music)
- Smells good, what's for breakfast?
- Well, since we're getting up so
late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
- Nice, brunch.
- Kind of, so I made
scrambled and soft-boiled eggs,
some French toast and buttermilk pancakes.
- Wow, you really went all out.
Did you make any coffee?
- Yeah, just the way you like it.
I also put out some cereal and musley
if you feel like having
something more light.
- Looks good.
- I'll squeeze that
some fresh orange juice.
- Get the jam and butter
while you're in there.
Oh, and don't forget the syrup.
- All righty.
- All right, we're back.
So a lot of interesting
things are huge breakfast.
- Way too big for me.
I don't like to eat a big
breakfast because I feel like
it makes me tired and
then I don't have any energy.
- Especially if you just get up, right?
- Exactly.
You need to shower and maybe
have some fruit and then go to work.
- You can talk about it that at the end.
There were a lot of interesting
words and phrases that we
heard that we would benefit
from taking a closer look at.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so on language
takeaway today, we're gonna
take a look at our first word
and it's an interesting word.
It's kind of a mix of two things, brunch.
That's right.
So this word comes
from two different words,
breakfast, bruh, bruh,
breakfast, and lunch.
- That's right.
- So brunch.
So if you have brunch,
what is exactly a brunch?
- Well, there's two ways to look at brunch.
One is the time element.
Usually brunch is later than breakfast,
but maybe a little earlier than lunch.
So 11 o'clock or maybe even noon.
But the other thing is size.
Because you're putting two meals
together, usually brunch is very big.
You eat a lot of food.
- Okay, so it's a perfect
combination of breakfast and lunch.
I'm the type of person that
likes having scrambled eggs
that noon, so this is a
perfect solution, brunch.
- Right, you don't have to only eat eggs.
At breakfast, you can
eat them at lunch as well.
- Exactly.
- This is actually something we do
a lot in America for Mother's Day.
So mom, wake us up late.
We take her to brunch.
It's a very big special meal.
- Very good.
And talking about eggs and the
types of eggs that we can have,
I mentioned scrambled eggs and in the
dialogue, we also heard soft boiled eggs.
- Okay, these are two very
important kinds of eggs.
Usually if you're in a restaurant,
they will ask you, how do you
want your eggs cooked or done?
And my answer is always scrambled.
- Scrambled.
- This means someone
mixes the eggs before they
are cooked, and then when
they cook, they are hard.
They're yellow.
- Okay.
- There's no white.
It's just yellow and
it's a little hard mixture.
But soft boiled eggs
are very, very different.
- That's right, soft boiled eggs, you
actually don't break the egg or open the egg
to cook it like in scrambled eggs.
You actually put the
entire egg in boiling water.
I think it's for two minutes,
and then you take it out.
And then you open the shell
and the eggs are kind of cooked.
It's kind of hard in some parts, but
it's also kind of liquidy in other parts.
- That's right, so the
outside, the white part is hard.
But the yellow part, the yolk, is liquid.
It's not hard.
- That's right, and actually
if you want the whole egg
to be hard, you can
ask for hard boiled eggs.
- That's right, those are
cooked for much longer.
- That's right, okay.
So we have scrambled
eggs, soft boiled eggs,
we have French toast, and
we have buttermilk pancakes.
- Okay, so you can ask for just pancakes.
But if you want to be specific,
you want to give
instructions about what kind
of pancakes you can ask
for buttermilk pancakes.
- And what exactly is buttermilk?
- Buttermilk is a very, very
creamy eggy milk that's very,
very high in fat, that makes
everything taste better.
- I think this is used a lot in baking,
not really in other kinds of foods,
so you can have buttermilk
muffins or buttermilk biscuits.
But usually you have buttermilk pancakes,
and so these are very
rich, very fatty pancakes.
- Awesome, yeah, they taste delicious.
All right, so now if we
want to eat a little bit
more healthy, we do have
some cereal and some musley.
- Musley is a funny word, it's not a sound,
we make very often in English, musley.
I think it actually comes from German.
- It does look German.
- Because actually the spelling is M-U-E,
so you would kind of want to
say muyezli, muyezli, or something.
- Yeah, no, we say
musley, and it's basically a
mixture of granola or
different kinds of fiber grains.
- Grains, mm-hmm.
- Yeah, so just think
of having like raisins
and maybe some almonds,
granola, all mixed up,
and you have this nice thing
that goes well with yogurt, musley.
- It's very, very tasty and
also very good for you.
- Okay, and now, well,
actually going back to pancakes,
no pancake is possible to eat,
unless you put syrup on it, right?
- Well, some people might disagree.
I know a lot of people who
eat pancakes with honey
or butter, but the best,
I think, is with syrup.
And syrup is basically liquid sugar,
and you put it on your
pancakes to make them sweeter.
- Okay, actually, the
same thing as honey,
basically, except that it
doesn't come from beans.
- Right, so real syrup, we say maple syrup,
comes from maple
trees, and you tap the tree,
and it comes out, and
it's very, very sweet.
But we also have syrup,
you can buy it the store,
which is man-made, yeah,
it's basically just sugar.
- Okay, very good, so that's
what we have with pancakes,
usually, but why don't we go
back, listen to our dialogue again.
Let's review all of these
yummy breakfast treats,
and we'll come back in
a bit with fluency builder.
(upbeat music)
- Smells good, what's for breakfast?
- Well, since we're getting up so
late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
- Nice, brunch.
- Kind of, so I made
scrambled and soft-willed
eggs, some French toast
and buttermilk pancakes.
- Wow, you really went all out.
Did you make any coffee?
- Yeah, just the way you like it.
I also put out some cereal,
and musally, if you feel like
having something more light.
- Looks good, I'll squeeze
out some fresh orange juice.
- Get the jam and butter
while you are in there.
Oh, and don't forget the syrup.
- All righty.
- All right, so now on fluency builder,
why don't we take a look
at a couple of phrases?
- Fluency builder.
- When the guy was kind of surprised,
he said, wow, you really went all out.
- Okay, so this comes from
the phrase to go all out.
So he went all out, or
I'm going to go all out.
And this means to give something
your best, to do more than is expected.
- That's right, so if you go all
out when you're making breakfast,
it means you just, you
cooked a lot or really
good, and you spend
a lot of time doing it.
- Or for example, if it's
someone's birthday, and I know
it's their birthday, I go all
out by buying gifts and a cake,
and lots of decorations and calling
all of their friends and having a party.
So this is doing everything for them.
- That's right, okay.
And he was really surprised,
and he really seemed
to enjoy breakfast,
and he said, looks good.
- Okay, this is a way to say
good job, or nicely done.
It's almost a way to
say, I'm happy about this.
- Or yeah, and obviously you can also say
that the food looks
delicious, so it looks good.
- It looks good, so it's
a way to say, you know,
well done, looks good, or
in this case, looks very tasty.
- That's right, okay.
And now this is an interesting part.
He says, "I'll squeeze us
some fresh orange juice.
" So let's take a look
at this verb, squeeze.
To squeeze, this is
something you usually do
with your hand when
you tighten something.
- So for example, your toothpaste.
- Yes, you squeeze your toothpaste,
so the toothpaste will come out.
- So in this case, we are squeezing
the orange juice to extract the juice.
- That's right, so you hold the orange
right tight, you make the juice come out,
and then you have fresh
squeezed orange juice.
And this is different from
orange juice you buy in a store.
- Okay, so you can say, "I'll
squeeze us some fresh orange juice.
" That means you're going
to make fresh orange juice,
and this fresh orange juice that you
make is called fresh squeezed orange juice.
- Fresh squeezed.
You're probably seeing this
in the store like some bottles,
they say 100% fresh squeezed
orange juice or something.
- Yeah, it's good for advertising.
- All right, so very good.
A lot of great interesting phrases there,
why don't we listen to
our dialogue one last time.
(upbeat music)
- Smells good, what's for breakfast?
- Well, since we're getting up so
late, I decided to make a big breakfast.
- Nice, brunch.
- Kind of, so I made
scrambled and soft boiled
eggs, some French toast
and buttermilk pancakes.
- Wow, you really went all out.
Did you make any coffee?
- Yeah, just the way you like it.
I also put out some cereal, and musley, if
you feel like having something more light.
- Looks good, I'll squeeze
us some fresh orange juice.
- Give the jam and butter
while you're in there.
Oh, and don't forget to syrup.
- All righty.
- All right, so talking
about brunch and
breakfast, what is your
typical or ideal breakfast?
- Oh, that's a hard question.
Breakfast is my favorite meal of the day,
so I could eat breakfast, all
kinds of breakfast anytime.
But one of my favorite kinds of
breakfast is a Greek diner breakfast.
- Greek diner, what does this have?
- Okay, well, we have
a lot of diners or small
restaurants that are very,
very cheap and fast in America.
And it's usually involved
some scrambled eggs
that are made with cheese
and toast and potatoes
and bacon and sausage and a coffee.
- Wow.
- Big breakfast, but delicious.
- Nice.
- What's your favorite?
- I also, in really, really
like breakfast, and I actually
like having places that you
can have 24 hour a day breakfast.
All day breakfast is called.
So I can have breakfast for dinner.
- Right, that's usually in America.
You go to a diner
because they have breakfast
at four o'clock in the morning
or at seven o'clock at night.
- I'm not really a coffee person.
I actually enjoy either
juice, orange juice,
or hot chocolate, I
really like hot chocolate.
And definitely pancakes, three
buttermilk pancakes stacked.
And as you said before, syrup,
but I actually also put butter on it.
- Gross, I know a lot
of people who do that,
and they put butter on first
and then they pour the syrup.
- Yeah, of course.
So it's like very, very
fatty and hash browns.
I'm definitely a fat enough hash browns.
- Those are potatoes that are chopped very,
very finely and you fry them together.
So it almost becomes like a
potato pancake, yeah, exactly.
So a lot of great stuff.
And obviously, breakfast
around the world are different.
I know, for example, in some countries,
they have the fisherman's breakfast.
So in the morning, you
have black coffee, rice,
and fish, that's right, because
you're gonna work all day.
So we're really curious
about how breakfast is
in your country, what a
typical breakfast is like.
- Yeah, what are traditional breakfast?
And what is your favorite breakfast?
Let us know on our
website, EnglishPod.
com, we hope to see you there.
- All right, bye, bye.
(upbeat music)